

### CONTACT ME AT

- George-stephenson-str., Berlin
- suchi.dey@nusmba.biz
- +49 1514345 7545
- in @suchandra-dey

# SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• Product strategy
- •••• OKR planning
- •••• Data infrastructure PM
- •••• Business analysis
- ••••• Stakeholder management
- •••• SQL
- •••• MicroStrategy
- ••• Google analytics

# LEADERSHIP & AWARDS

- President, Social Impact club, Student Council NUS MBA (2015)
- Women in business award, NUS MBA (2015)
- Top Writer, Women studies, QUORA (2015)
- Applause award for being a team player, Deloitte (2013)

# SUCHANDRA DEY

# TECHNICAL PRODUCT MANAGER

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

I have ~10 years of experience in agile teams as a product manager and technology consultant across diverse verticals. I excel at hypothesis-driven strategy formulation, ideation, scoping, planning and ensuring quantifiable results within strict deadlines. I thrive in customer-centric environments and specialise in bringing together teams across functions to achieve a common goal.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Technical Product Manager

ZALANDO SE | Berlin | Jan 2022 - Present

- Shaping the data strategy for Zalando group, taking a central role in conception and implementation of scalable data products across 500+ teams
- Leading a global, cross-departmental project to provide a compliant, system-agnostic, scalable data access provisioning infrastructure impacting 5k internal users
- Managing a team of 3 data product managers to deliver components of the large scale data platform
- Key contributor and advocate to the evolution of principles and best-practice for data management, governance, architecture, quality

## Technical Product Manager

SCOUT24 AG | Berlin | Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- Driving the vision for Scout24's data platform including tools for data storage, transformation, orchestration & BI
- Leading a complex, high-stakes project to provide a 100% GDPR compliant data infrastructure, saving \$20M to the company in compliance costs
- Guiding a team of 10 engineers including senior data & BI experts to transform the current data platform
- Managing 3 distributed data teams; inculcating a customer-first mindset to steer our platform towards high performance & ease of use
- Mentoring & coaching PMs, junior engineers through regular 1:1s to instill & nurture Scout's core values

#### LANGUAGES

- ## English
  Native or bilingual proficiency
- German
  Elementary proficiency (A1+)
- Hindi
  Native or bilingual proficiency
- Bengali
  Native or bilingual proficiency

# PASSION PROJECTS & CERITIFICATIONS

- Data PM Nanodegree

  Completed the nanodegree program for
  Data Product management from Udacity
- ☆ ProductTank (05/2019 12/2019)
  Gave talks on topics related to product management to a community of PMs
- Annoted (04/2020 Present)

  Currently developing an innovative notes app on iOS and Android

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

- Campaign volunteer for girls2pioneer, UN Women (2018)
- Mentor for social entrepreneurs,
  Singapore International
  foundation (2017)
- Organized events for MBA cohort on Impact Investment with <u>IIX</u> <u>Asia</u> and <u>Shujog</u> (2016)

#### INTERESTS

- Social entrepreneurship
- Impact investing
- Writing/Storytelling
- Travelling
- Science fiction
- Pets

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Product Manager**

DOCDOC PTE LTD | Singapore | Oct 2018 - Jul 2020

- Solely managed the core product 'doctor discovery'
   (B2B2C) from ideation through launch growing 1M+ users
- Mentored new product managers, instilling agile best practices, streamlining processes during PDLC
- Ensured robust prototyping, maximising sprint success to 100%
- Establishing robust metrics to assess product progress; improving adoption and engagement KPIs

#### Consultant

M-BRAIN GROUP | Singapore | Feb 2017 - Sept 2018

- Delivered key strategy projects as the lead PM; scoping planning, execution, team & stakeholder management
- Served high-stakes clients with deep market research projects such as NPS studies, market sizing/entry projects
- Published 10+ strategy research papers on client publication sites

# Co-founder

KS APPAREL (BRAND- CARVE) | Calcutta | Aug 2014 - Jul 2015

- Launched an apparel brand CARVE; turned it cash positive in 1.5 years
- Partnered with fashion retailers-Amazon.in, Flipkart.in;
   built & facilitated e-commerce sales from ground up
- Managed P&Ls, and led a team of marketing associates

## **Business Analyst**

DELOITTE CONSULTING LLP | Hyderabad | Jun 2011 - Aug 2014

- Used scrum best practices to help team of 200+ to increase their velocity by 2x
- Enabled client CTO desk with data analytics and presentations using SQL and Excel with quick turnaround

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

#### NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE

Masters in business administration (MBA) | Aug 2015 - Dec 2016

- First class with distinction
- Specialization: Stategy & Finance

#### BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Bachelors in engineering (B.Tech) | May 2007 - Jun 2011

- First class with distinction
- Department: Computer Science